Getting into trouble is easy but getting out of it is all the fun!
Girls Just Want to Have Fun is a comedy, family,
music film directed by Alan Metter.
Janey is new in town.
She soon meets Lynne, a classmate who shares her
passion for the local show 'Dance TV'.
When a competition is announced to find new Dance TV
performers, Janey and Lynne are determined to audition.
The only problem is that Janey's father doesn't approve of that kind of thing.
Janey Glenn, played by Sarah Jessica Parker.
Lynne Stone, played by Helen Hunt.
Maggie Malene, played by Shannen Doherty.
Jeff Malene, played by Lee Montgomery.
J.P. Sands, played by Morgan Woodward.
Drew Boreman, played by Jonathan Silverman.
Girls Just Want to Have Fun is a 1985 American romantic comedy dance film
directed by Alan Metter and distributed by New World Pictures.
It was written by Amy Spies and stars Sarah Jessica Parker, Lee Montgomery,
Morgan Woodward, Jonathan Silverman, Shannen Doherty, and Helen Hunt.
Its story follows Janey, a new girl in town who meets Lynne and discovers
they both share a passion for dancing and the TV show Dance TV.
Together the two enter a competition to be a new Dance TV regular
couple; however, Janey's father does not approve.
The film was produced by Chuck Russell and was released on April 12, 1985.
It grossed $1.7 million in its opening weekend and $6.3
million worldwide, against a budget of $5 million.
Despite this, the film was regularly aired on cable TV for
several years and has become a cult film.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois,
dancing, dance competition, catholic school.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.